# Kang-wook Kim

■ full324@snu.ac.kr | 🗥 kwkim.me | 😱 wookladin | 🛅 Kang-wook Kim

### **SUMMARY**

I am an undergraduate student majoring in ECE at Seoul National University. I am currently a research intern at Supertone Inc., where I am conducting research on speech/singing voice synthesis. Previously, I held a position as a senior research scientist at MINDsLab Inc., where I focused on speech synthesis.

My goal is to develop user-friendly AI techniques that can benefit humanity. I always focus on improving the usability of my AI model from the user's point of view, and I love these works.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

MINDsLab Inc.

Mar. 2020 – Mar. 2022

Senior Al Scientist Pangyo, Kyeonggi

- Worked as the leader of the speech synthesis team, responsible for developing Text-to-Speech (TTS)
  architectures and training recipes used in various applications such as the Twitch donation system, weather
  forecasts, and Al Human.
- Developed a robust autoregressive TTS system capable of generating long sentences, with a maximum output of 10 minutes of speech.
- Improved the sound quality and inference speed of the TTS system, resulting in a **mean opinion score increase from 3.84 to 4.18**, which is comparable to the **ground-truth value of 4.47**.
- Built a pronunciation evaluation engine for foreigners using a small and unrefined dataset (4hrs, 12 speakers), achieving 92% accuracy on unseen data from speakers.
- Improved the sound quality of the voice conversion system, resulting in mean opinion scores for **naturality and speaker similarity** that are comparable to ground-truth.
- Served as a substitute for mandatory military service from Mar. 2020 to Feb. 2022.

Supertone Inc.

Apr. 2022 – Now

Research Intern Seoul

- Currently working as a part-time research intern during the semester and full-time during vacation.
- Conducting research aimed at increasing the phoneme classification accuracy of singing voices.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Seoul National University**

B.S. in Electronical and Computer Engineering (Overall GPA: 3.99/4.30) (Major: 4.07/4.30)

Mar. 2018 - Now

High school for gifted students in mathematics, science, and informatics

Seoul, Korea

## **Gyeonggi Science High School for the gifted**Mar. 2015 – Feb. 2018

Gyeonggi, Korea

#### **PUBLICATION**

#### Conference

 Kang-wook Kim, Seung-won Park, Junhyeok Lee, and Myun-chul Joe, "Assem-VC: Realistic Voice Conversion by Assembling Modern Speech Synthesis Techniques," *Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2022*

#### Workshop

Kang-wook Kim and Junhyeok Lee, "Controllable and Interpretable Singing Voice Decomposition via Assem-VC,"
 NeurIPS Workshop on ML for Creativity and Design 2021 (Oral)

Ki-Ung Song\*, Dongseok Shim\*, Kang-wook Kim\*, Jae-young Lee, Younggeun Kim, "FS-NCSR: Increasing Diversity
of the Super-Resolution Space via Frequency Separation and Noise-Conditioned Normalizing Flow," CVPR NTIRE
Workshop 2022

### **Demo Track**

 Hyoung-Kyu Song, Sang Hoon Woo, Junhyeok Lee, Seungmin Yang, Hyunjae Cho, Dongho Choi, Kang-wook Kim, Youseong Lee, "Talking Face Generation with Multilingual TTS," CVPR Demo Track 2022

#### **OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTION**

Assem-VC - voice conversion system (Stars: 203): Official repository of our paper.

UnivNet - vocoder (Stars: 135): I reproduced the results in the paper while official implementation is unavailable.

### **HONORS and AWARDS**

- Presidential scholarship on informatics 2018 2023, fully funded scholarschip for undergrad course
- · Hanseong Sonjaehan Scholarship 2016 2017, 5M KRW per year
- Exemplary Youth Awards in Gyeonggi-do 2016, Science and Technology sector
- Korea Olympiad in Informatics (KOI) Gold (4th place) at 2015; Silver, Bronze at 2014, 2011.
- Completion of winter school for International Physics Olympiad (IPhO) candidates 2015, 2016